<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Eyegrade (eyegrade)</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/categories/eyegrade.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 13:31:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Eyegrade 0.4.4 released</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-044-released.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've just released Eyegrade 0.4.4.
This version fixes a bug introduced by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-043-released.html"&gt;the bugfix of version 0.4.3&lt;/a&gt;.
Version 0.4.3 solved the problem for
the older versions of Python,
but inadvertently introduced exactly the same problem
for the newer versions,
which were previously unaffected.
I've reverted the erroneous fix
and solved the problem
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade/commit/e03da3762e748913db89e6470b3fe85b02f367df"&gt;in a better way&lt;/a&gt;.
This new version should be able to export grades
in any 2.6 and 2.7 version of Python,
both Windows and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the only change with respect to version 0.4.3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have installed Eyegrade through &lt;em&gt;git&lt;/em&gt;,
you can easily update the program by executing the command
&lt;em&gt;git pull&lt;/em&gt; from inside the directory in which Eyegrade is installed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bugfix</category><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-044-released.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 17:46:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eyegrade 0.4.3 released</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-043-released.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've just released Eyegrade 0.4.3.
This release fixes a bug
that made the functionality that exports grades fail
when the program is run
with the Python 2.6 version I distribute for Windows.
Linux users with a reasonably recent version of Python
were not affected.
This is the only change with respect to version 0.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have installed Eyegrade through &lt;em&gt;git&lt;/em&gt;, you can easily update
the program by executing the command
&lt;em&gt;git pull&lt;/em&gt; from inside the directory in which Eyegrade is installed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bugfix</category><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-043-released.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 18:43:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Improved documentation about how to edit an exam with LaTeX</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/improved-documentation-about-how-to-edit-an-exam-with-latex.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;official&lt;/em&gt; way of editting your exams for Eyegrade
consists of creating an XML file with the questions,
running on it the &lt;cite&gt;create_exam&lt;/cite&gt; script provided by Eyegrade
and compiling the resulting files with LaTeX
in order to get the final PDF documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although exams can also be edited
with a word processor such as OpenOffice or Microsoft Word
(see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eyegrade.org/doc/user-manual/#creating-the-exams-in-a-word-processor"&gt;Creating the exams in a word processor&lt;/a&gt;),
following the official way has some advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eyegrade shuffles the questions
and produces several models with different question orderings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eyegrade creates the exam configuration file (the &lt;cite&gt;.eye&lt;/cite&gt; file)
automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LaTeX-style equations may be used inside the questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, editing an XML file and dealing with LaTeX
may scare some users
that are more used to graphical word processors.
In order to make the procedure more approachable,
the user manual describes now more in depth how to edit exams
the official way in the section
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eyegrade.org/doc/user-manual/#editing-exams"&gt;Editing exams&lt;/a&gt;.
Suggestions on how to improve that section further
are most welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>documentation</category><category>eyegrade</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/improved-documentation-about-how-to-edit-an-exam-with-latex.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 23:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eyegrade 0.4 released!</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-04-released.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've released eyegrade 0.4 (actually, eyegrade 0.4.2 after a couple of
minor changes and a bug fix). There is only one main change in this
release with respect to the 0.3 series, the ability to export grade
listings from the user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you select in the menu &lt;em&gt;Exams / Export grade listing&lt;/em&gt; you get a dialog
like the following one that allows you to configure the export options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="The new export dialog." class="thumbnail" src="http://www.eyegrade.org/galleries/screenshots-04/export-dialog.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new feature is easier to use and more flexible than the
&lt;cite&gt;mix_grades&lt;/cite&gt; script that was available in the previous versions. The
script is now obsolete and will probably be removed in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-04-released.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 18:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eyegrade 0.3 released!</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-03-released.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've just released eyegrade 0.3. The main changes in this version are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previously, exams could only be reviewed immediately after capturing
them. Now you can review the exams, change answers or change the
student id any time you open the session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A consequence of the previous change is that now grading does not
start automatically when the session is opened. Once you open a
session, you can view or edit the exams you have already graded, or
click on the &lt;em&gt;Start grading&lt;/em&gt; action in the menu / toolbar in order
to start grading more exams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graphical user interface is now prepared for translations. This
release features an interface in English, Spanish, Galician and
Catalan. Volunteers for other languages are welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are changes to the layout of the graphical user
interface. There is a vertical area at the left were the thumbnails
of the exams graded for this session are displayed. In addition,
there is a new status bar at the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware that the sessions created with eyegrade 0.3 are not
compatible with previous versions. Conversely, sessions created with
previous versions cannot be opened with eyegrade 0.3. The reason is
that now session are stored internally as a SQLite database and store
more information about the exams than the previous versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have installed eyegrade through &lt;em&gt;git&lt;/em&gt;, you can easily update
the program from versions in the series 0.2.x by executing the command
&lt;em&gt;git pull&lt;/em&gt; from inside the directory in which eyegrade is installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find bugs or problems with this new release, please open an
issue at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade/"&gt;the GitHub project page&lt;/a&gt;, or just let me know by
commenting on this post or sending me an email.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-03-released.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eyegrade moved to a new location</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-moved-to-a-new-location.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've just moved Eyegrade to a new Web location at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eyegrade.org/"&gt;eyegrade.org&lt;/a&gt;. These are the important links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project homepage: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eyegrade.org/"&gt;http://eyegrade.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User manual: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eyegrade.org/doc/user-manual/"&gt;http://eyegrade.org/doc/user-manual/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eyegrade.org/blog/"&gt;http://eyegrade.org/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS feed: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eyegrade.org/blog/rss.xml"&gt;http://eyegrade.org/blog/rss.xml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requests for the old addresses will automatically be redirected to the
new location. However, the old server may be down for some periods of
August. In fact, the frequent downtimes of the old hosting are one of
the main reasons for the change. During those downtime periods
redirections won't work. However, the new addresses will work properly
even in that case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new website is hosted at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; service. My experience so far with this
service has been very satisfactory. The availability of the website
with the new hosting will definitely be much better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-moved-to-a-new-location.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 16:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Requests for Eyegrade 0.3</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/requests-for-eyegrade-03.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm planning the next major release (0.3) of Eyegrade for
September. There are some features I have in mind, but listening to
the users from time to time does not harm ;) If there is a feature you
are especially interested in, just let me know by commenting on this
post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from some polishing here and there, these are things I'm
thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right now, you can review and fix detection errors in an exam only
at the moment you scan it. What if you discover an error later on?
It think it would be great if the interface allowed you to open a
grading session anytime later and use the same reviewing/fixing
features.  This feature would probably include a list of students
and grades in the interface, so that you can quickly access the exam
of a specific student.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user interface for entering the questions of an exam, creating the
PDFs, etc. This would probably include dropping LaTeX in favor of
something else (my main option is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.reportlab.com/software/opensource/"&gt;ReportLab library&lt;/a&gt;). Using the
current command-line interface and LaTeX would still be possible,
but not the preferred method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making life easier for users that only want to use Eyegrade for
grading, but not for creating the exams. I include here features
such as creating a &lt;cite&gt;.eye&lt;/cite&gt; file through guided dialogues or creating
the PDF of a personalized answer sheet in the user interface.  It's
about time to close &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade/issues/36"&gt;issue 36&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapting the user interface for multiple languages. I can start with
an English, Spanish and Galician interface, and wait for volunteers
to translate it to other tongues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't have time for all the features in the list, so you can help me
to prioritize. Of course, you can also request features not in the
list ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>requests</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/requests-for-eyegrade-03.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 18:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eyegrade 0.2 released!</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/release-eyegrade-0.2.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eyegrade 0.2 has been released! It features the shiny new PyQt-based
user interface that I showed in previous posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.uc3m.es/jaf/eyegrade/doc/user-manual/"&gt;Eyegrade User Manual&lt;/a&gt; contains
up-to-date instructions for using the new interface. If you have
Eyegrade 0.1.x installed, you need to install PyQt and change the
value of an environment variable. See the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.uc3m.es/jaf/eyegrade/doc/user-manual/#upgrading-from-eyegrade-0-1-x-to-eyegrade-0-2"&gt;section about upgrading
Eyegrade&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new user interface will facilitate other usability improvements
in the future, such as the possibility of reviewing previously graded
exams, editing the student list, writing grades to disk in several
orders and formats, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you experience problems with this new version, please let me know
by commenting on this blog or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade/issues?sort=created&amp;amp;state=open"&gt;posting an issue at GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/release-eyegrade-0.2.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Preview of the improved new-session dialog</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/preview-of-the-improved-new-session-dialog.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been working on the &lt;em&gt;new session&lt;/em&gt; dialog. Now it is a wizard with
three pages. The main novelties are that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select more than one student list. All of them are used
when detecting the student id.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now enter the scores for correct and incorrect answers. If
the exam configuration file already contains the scores, you'll see
them as default values. In addition, you can let Eyegrade choose
appropriate values for you, by just entering the maximum score of
the exam and choosing whether incorrect answers should penalize or
not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try the new dialog in the development branch at GitHub, and
see it this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eyegrade.org/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-2/"&gt;screenshots gallery&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Screenshot of a page of the new session dialog" class="thumbnail" src="http://www.eyegrade.org/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-2/screenshot-3.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new dialog will appear in the 0.2 release. I have in mind for a
future release the possibility of entering the exam configuration from
the new session dialog, as an alternative to reading it from a
file. This may be handy for users who do not create the exam with the
command line tools that Eyegrade provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments and suggestions are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>pyqt</category><category>screenshots</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/preview-of-the-improved-new-session-dialog.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 22:49:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Teaser of the new PyQt-based eyegrade user interface</title><link>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/teaser-of-the-new-pyqt-based-eyegrade-user-interface.html</link><dc:creator>Jesús Arias Fisteus</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm programming from scratch the graphical user interface of
Eyegrade. The old user interface uses Pygame. It allowed me to build
the first interface of the program very quickly, but its lack of
graphical components (buttons, dialogues, menus, etc.) was preventing me
from programming a more user-friendly interface.  I've decided to use
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.riverbankcomputing.co.uk/software/pyqt/"&gt;PyQt&lt;/a&gt; for the
new interface. Why PyQt? I programmed a game with Qt in C++ many years
ago, and I liked the library a lot. With the python bindings, it is
even easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new user interface will be released with Eyegrade 0.2 (hopefully,
before the end of January). Check the first &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eyegrade.org/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-1/"&gt;screenshots gallery&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Screenshot of the new user interface of Eyegrade" class="thumbnail" src="http://www.eyegrade.org/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-1/screenshot-4.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now the program does more or less the same as the old interface,
but it will be easier to add new features in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brave can give it a try before the release (it is available at the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade"&gt;development branch of Eyegrade at GitHub&lt;/a&gt;). Suggestions are welcome
(just post a comment here or write me an email.) I have tested it only
in Linux, although it should work in Windows too. If you try it, notice that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need PyQt (package &lt;em&gt;python-qt4&lt;/em&gt; in Debian and Ubuntu).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no &lt;cite&gt;src&lt;/cite&gt; directory anymore. Following the Python
conventions, the Python files are now directly under the &lt;cite&gt;eyegrade&lt;/cite&gt;
subdirectory of the main directory of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main program does not receive command line arguments. The &lt;cite&gt;.eye&lt;/cite&gt;
file and student list are selected at the &lt;em&gt;new session&lt;/em&gt; dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>pyqt</category><category>screenshots</category><guid>http://www.eyegrade.org/blog/posts/teaser-of-the-new-pyqt-based-eyegrade-user-interface.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>