<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Eyegrade Blog (release)</title><link>http://eyegrade.org/blog</link><description>Blog for the free software tool Eyegrade</description><atom:link href="http://eyegrade.org/categories/release.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 18:18:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>nikola</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Eyegrade 0.4 released!</title><link>http://eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-04-released.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've release eyegrade 0.4 (actually, eyegrade 0.4.2 after a couple of
minor changes and a bug fix). There is only one main change in this
release with respect to the 0.3 series, the ability to export grade
listings from the user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you select in the menu &lt;em&gt;Exams / Export grade listing&lt;/em&gt; you get a dialog
like the following one that allows you to configure the export options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="The new export dialog." class="thumbnail" src="http://eyegrade.org/galleries/screenshots-04/export-dialog.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new feature is easier to use and more flexible than the
&lt;cite&gt;mix_grades&lt;/cite&gt; script that was available in the previous versions. The
script is now obsolete and will probably be removed in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-04-released.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 17:58:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eyegrade 0.3 released!</title><link>http://eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-03-released.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've just released eyegrade 0.3. The main changes in this version are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previously, exams could only be reviewed immediately after capturing
them. Now you can review the exams, change answers or change the
student id any time you open the session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A consequence of the previous change is that now grading does not
start automatically when the session is opened. Once you open a
session, you can view or edit the exams you have already graded, or
click on the &lt;em&gt;Start grading&lt;/em&gt; action in the menu / toolbar in order
to start grading more exams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graphical user interface is now prepared for translations. This
release features an interface in English, Spanish, Galician and
Catalan. Volunteers for other languages are welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are changes to the layout of the graphical user
interface. There is a vertical area at the left were the thumbnails
of the exams graded for this session are displayed. In addition,
there is a new status bar at the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware that the sessions created with eyegrade 0.3 are not
compatible with previous versions. Conversely, sessions created with
previous versions cannot be opened with eyegrade 0.3. The reason is
that now session are stored internally as a SQLite database and store
more information about the exams than the previous versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have installed eyegrade through &lt;em&gt;git&lt;/em&gt;, you can easily update
the program from versions in the series 0.2.x by executing the command
&lt;em&gt;git pull&lt;/em&gt; from inside the directory in which eyegrade is installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find bugs or problems with this new release, please open an
issue at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade/"&gt;the GitHub project page&lt;/a&gt;, or just let me know by
commenting on this post or sending me an email.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://eyegrade.org/blog/posts/eyegrade-03-released.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eyegrade 0.2 released!</title><link>http://eyegrade.org/blog/posts/release-eyegrade-0.2.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eyegrade 0.2 has been released! It features the shiny new PyQt-based
user interface that I showed in previous posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.uc3m.es/jaf/eyegrade/doc/user-manual/"&gt;Eyegrade User Manual&lt;/a&gt; contains
up-to-date instructions for using the new interface. If you have
Eyegrade 0.1.x installed, you need to install PyQt and change the
value of an environment variable. See the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.it.uc3m.es/jaf/eyegrade/doc/user-manual/#upgrading-from-eyegrade-0-1-x-to-eyegrade-0-2"&gt;section about upgrading
Eyegrade&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new user interface will facilitate other usability improvements
in the future, such as the possibility of reviewing previously graded
exams, editing the student list, writing grades to disk in several
orders and formats, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you experience problems with this new version, please let me know
by commenting on this blog or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade/issues?sort=created&amp;amp;state=open"&gt;posting an issue at GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>release</category><guid>http://eyegrade.org/blog/posts/release-eyegrade-0.2.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>