<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>The Eyegrade Blog (requests)</title><link>The Eyegrade Blog</link><description>Blog for the free software tool Eyegrade</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 18:40:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>nikola</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Requests for Eyegrade 0.3</title><link>The Eyegrade Blog/posts/requests-for-eyegrade-03.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm planning the next major release (0.3) of Eyegrade for
September. There are some features I have in mind, but listening to
the users from time to time does not harm ;) If there is a feature you
are especially interested in, just let me know by commenting on this
post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from some polishing here and there, these are things I'm
thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right now, you can review and fix detection errors in an exam only
at the moment you scan it. What if you discover an error later on?
It think it would be great if the interface allowed you to open a
grading session anytime later and use the same reviewing/fixing
features.  This feature would probably include a list of students
and grades in the interface, so that you can quickly access the exam
of a specific student.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user interface for entering the questions of an exam, creating the
PDFs, etc. This would probably include dropping LaTeX in favor of
something else (my main option is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.reportlab.com/software/opensource/"&gt;ReportLab library&lt;/a&gt;). Using the
current command-line interface and LaTeX would still be possible,
but not the preferred method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making life easier for users that only want to use Eyegrade for
grading, but not for creating the exams. I include here features
such as creating a &lt;cite&gt;.eye&lt;/cite&gt; file through guided dialogues or creating
the PDF of a personalized answer sheet in the user interface.  It's
about time to close &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade/issues/36"&gt;issue 36&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapting the user interface for multiple languages. I can start with
an English, Spanish and Galician interface, and wait for volunteers
to translate it to other tongues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't have time for all the features in the list, so you can help me
to prioritize. Of course, you can also request features not in the
list ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>requests</category><guid>The Eyegrade Blog/posts/requests-for-eyegrade-03.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 18:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>