<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>The Eyegrade Blog (screenshots)</title><link>The Eyegrade Blog</link><description>Blog for the free software tool Eyegrade</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 18:40:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>nikola</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Preview of the improved new-session dialog</title><link>The Eyegrade Blog/posts/preview-of-the-improved-new-session-dialog.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been working on the &lt;em&gt;new session&lt;/em&gt; dialog. Now it is a wizard with
three pages. The main novelties are that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select more than one student list. All of them are used
when detecting the student id.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now enter the scores for correct and incorrect answers. If
the exam configuration file already contains the scores, you'll see
them as default values. In addition, you can let Eyegrade choose
appropriate values for you, by just entering the maximum score of
the exam and choosing whether incorrect answers should penalize or
not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try the new dialog in the development branch at GitHub, and
see it this &lt;a class="reference external" href="/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-2/"&gt;screenshots gallery&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Screenshot of a page of the new session dialog" class="thumbnail" src="/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-2/screenshot-3.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new dialog will appear in the 0.2 release. I have in mind for a
future release the possibility of entering the exam configuration from
the new session dialog, as an alternative to reading it from a
file. This may be handy for users who do not create the exam with the
command line tools that Eyegrade provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments and suggestions are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>screenshots</category><category>pyqt</category><guid>The Eyegrade Blog/posts/preview-of-the-improved-new-session-dialog.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 22:49:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Teaser of the new PyQt-based eyegrade user interface</title><link>The Eyegrade Blog/posts/teaser-of-the-new-pyqt-based-eyegrade-user-interface.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm programming from scratch the graphical user interface of
Eyegrade. The old user interface uses Pygame. It allowed me to build
the first interface of the program very quickly, but its lack of
graphical components (buttons, dialogues, menus, etc.) was preventing me
from programming a more user-friendly interface.  I've decided to use
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.riverbankcomputing.co.uk/software/pyqt/"&gt;PyQt&lt;/a&gt; for the
new interface. Why PyQt? I programmed a game with Qt in C++ many years
ago, and I liked the library a lot. With the python bindings, it is
even easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new user interface will be released with Eyegrade 0.2 (hopefully,
before the end of January). Check the first &lt;a class="reference external" href="/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-1/"&gt;screenshots gallery&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Screenshot of the new user interface of Eyegrade" class="thumbnail" src="/galleries/screenshots-new-gui-1/screenshot-4.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now the program does more or less the same as the old interface,
but it will be easier to add new features in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brave can give it a try before the release (it is available at the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jfisteus/eyegrade"&gt;development branch of Eyegrade at GitHub&lt;/a&gt;). Suggestions are welcome
(just post a comment here or write me an email.) I have tested it only
in Linux, although it should work in Windows too. If you try it, notice that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need PyQt (package &lt;em&gt;python-qt4&lt;/em&gt; in Debian and Ubuntu).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no &lt;cite&gt;src&lt;/cite&gt; directory anymore. Following the Python
conventions, the Python files are now directly under the &lt;cite&gt;eyegrade&lt;/cite&gt;
subdirectory of the main directory of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main program does not receive command line arguments. The &lt;cite&gt;.eye&lt;/cite&gt;
file and student list are selected at the &lt;em&gt;new session&lt;/em&gt; dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>eyegrade</category><category>screenshots</category><category>pyqt</category><guid>The Eyegrade Blog/posts/teaser-of-the-new-pyqt-based-eyegrade-user-interface.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>